Five years ago, I had my dream job.
قبل خمس سنوات، كانت لدي وظيفة الأحلام.
I was a foreign correspondent in the Middle East
كنت مراسلة أجنبية في الشرق الأوسط .
reporting for ABC News.
أقدم التقارير لدى "إيه بي سي نيوز"
But there was a crack in the wall,
ولكن كان هناك صدْع في الجدار،
a problem with our industry,
مشكلة في صناعتنا،
that I felt we needed to fix.
والتي شعرت أننا بحاجة إلى إصلاحها.
You see, I got to the Middle East right around the end of 2007,
كما ترون، لقد وصلت إلى الشرق الأوسط في نهاية 2007،
which was just around the midpoint
أي في حوالى منتصف
of the Iraq War.
حرب العراق .
But by the time I got there, it was already nearly impossible
ولكن بحلول وقت وصولي إلى هناك، كان من المستحيل تقريبًا
to find stories about Iraq on air.
إيجاد تقارير تلفزيونية أو إذاعية عن العراق.
Coverage had dropped across the board,
انخفضت التغطية في جميع المجالات،
across networks.
وعبر جميع القنوات.
And of the stories that did make it,
وحتى التقارير التي تم بثها،
more than 80 percent of them were about us.
كانت أكثر من 80٪ منها عنا.
We were missing the stories about Iraq,
كنا نفتقر إلى قصص عن العراق،
the people who live there,
عن الناس الذين يعيشون هناك،
and what was happening to them under the weight of the war.
وما كان يحدث لهم تحت وطأة الحرب.
Afghanistan had already fallen off the agenda.
كانت أفغانستان قد خرجت عن نطاق التغطية.
There were less than one percent of all news stories in 2008
كان هناك أقل من واحد في المئة من مجمل القصص الإخبارية في عام 2008
that went to the war in Afghanistan.
التي تمحورت حول الحرب في أفغانستان.
It was the longest war in US history,
لقد كانت أطول حرب شهدها تاريخ الولايات المتحدة،
but information was so scarce
ولكن المعلومات كانت جدّ نادرة
that schoolteachers we spoke to
لدرجة أن المدرسين الذين تحدثنا إليهم
told us they had trouble explaining to their students
أخبرونا أنهم واجهوا صعوبة في شرح
what we were doing there,
ما كنا نفعله هناك لطلابهم،
when those students had parents
في حين كان لدى هؤلاء الطلاب آباء
who were fighting and sometimes dying overseas.
يقاتلون ويموتون أحيانًا في الخارج.
We had drawn a blank,
لقد رَجَعَنا بِخُفَيّ حُنَيْن .
and it wasn't just Iraq and Afghanistan.
ليس فقط في العراق وأفغانستان.
From conflict zones to climate change
بدءًا من مناطق الصراع مرورًا بتغير المناخ
to all sorts of issues around crises in public health,
انتهاءً إلى جميع أنواع القضايا حول الأزمات في مجال الصحة العامة،
we were missing what I call the species-level issues,
كنا نفتقد ما أسميه قضايا على مستوى الأنواع،
because as a species, they could actually sink us.
لأنها كنوع، بإمكانها في الواقع أن تتسبب في غرقِنا.
And by failing to understand the complex issues of our time,
وبفشلنا في فهم القضايا المعقدة في عصرنا،
we were facing certain practical implications.
كنا نواجه آثارًا عملية معينة.
How were we going to solve problems
كيف يمكننا حل مشاكل
that we didn't fundamentally understand,
لم نفهمها أساسًا،
that we couldn't track in real time,
لم نتمكن من رصدها أثناء حدوثها فعليًا،
and where the people working on the issues
وحيث كان الأشخاص الذين يعملون على هذه القضايا
were invisible to us
غير مرئيين لنا،
and sometimes invisible to each other?
وغير مرئيين أحيانًا لبعضهم البعض؟
When you look back on Iraq,
حينما نرجع بالذاكرة إلى العراق،
those years when we were missing the story,
إلى تلك السنوات التي كنا نفتقد فيها إلى القصة،
were the years when the society was falling apart,
كانت سنوات انهيار المجتمع،
when we were setting the conditions for what would become the rise of ISIS,
حينها كنا نهيئ ظروفًا ساهمت في نشأة داعش،
the ISIS takeover of Mosul
إستيلاء داعش على الموصل
and terrorist violence that would spread
والعنف الإرهابي الذي سوف ينتشر
beyond Iraq's borders to the rest of the world.
إلى ما وراء حدود العراق، في بقية العالم.
Just around that time where I was making that observation,
حوالي وقت إدلائي بتلك الملاحظة،
I looked across the border of Iraq
نظرت إلى ما وراء حدود العراق،
and noticed there was another story we were missing:
ولاحظت أن هناك قصة أخرى نفتقدها:
the war in Syria.
الحرب في سوريا.
If you were a Middle-East specialist, you knew that Syria was that important
إذا كنت متخصصًا في قضايا الشرق الأوسط، لعلمت بأن سوريا كانت مهمة
from the start.
منذ البداية.
But it ended up being, really,
ولكن انتهى بها المطاف، فعليًّا،
one of the forgotten stories of the Arab Spring.
كإحدى قصص الربيع العربي المنسية.
I saw the implications up front.
لقد توقعتُ الآثار منذ البداية.
Syria is intimately tied to regional security,
إن سوريا مرتبطة ارتباطًا وثيقًا بالأمن الإقليمي،
to global stability.
بالاستقرار العالمي.
I felt like we couldn't let that become
لقد شعرتُ أننا لا يمكن أن نسمح بأن تصير
another one of the stories we left behind.
قصة أخرى من القصص التي أهملناها.
So I left my big TV job to start a website, called "Syria Deeply."
لذلك تركت وظيفتي المهمة في التلفزيون لبدء موقع إلكتروني، يسمى "Syria Deeply."
It was designed to be a news and information source
تم تصميمه ليكون مصدرًا للأخبار والمعلومات
that made it easier to understand a complex issue,
الذي جعل من السهل أن نفهم مسألة معقدة،
and for the past four years, it's been a resource
وعلى مدى السنوات الأربع الماضية، كان منْهَلًا
for policymakers and professionals working on the conflict in Syria.
لصناع القرار والمهنيين العاملين على الصراع في سوريا.
We built a business model
قمنا ببناء نموذج عمل تجاري
based on consistent, high-quality information,
قائم على الاتساق، وعلي معلومات ذات جودة عالية،
and convening the top minds on the issue.
وجمع أفضل العقول في ما يتعلق بهذه القضية.
And we found it was a model that scaled.
واكتشفنا أنه كان نموذجا قابلاً للتوسع.
We got passionate requests to do other things "Deeply."
وصلتنا طلبات متحمسة للقيام بأمور أخرى "بعمق".
So we started to work our way down the list.
لذلك بدأنا العمل على تنفيذ هذه القائمة.
I'm just one of many entrepreneurs,
أنا مجرد إحدى رائدات الأعمال،
and we are just one of many start-ups
ونحن مجرد إحدى الشركات الناشئة
trying to fix what's wrong with news.
التي تحاول إصلاح ما هو خاطئ في الأخبار
All of us in the trenches know
كان كل واحد منا يعلم
that something is wrong with the news industry.
أن هناك خطب ما بصناعة الأخبار.
It's broken.
إنه معطل.
Trust in the media has hit an all-time low.
انخفضت نسبة الثقة في وسائل الإعلام إلى أدنى مستوى على الإطلاق.
And the statistic you're seeing up there is from September --
والإحصائيات اتي ترونها هناك تعود إلى سبتمبر--
it's arguably gotten worse.
لقد ازدادت سوءًا بلا شك.
But we can fix this.
لكن بإمكاننا إصلاح هذا.
We can fix the news.
يمكننا إصلاح الأخبار.
I know that that's true.
أنا أعلم أن هذا صحيح.
You can call me an idealist; I call myself an industrious optimist.
يمكنكم وصفي بالمثالية؛ أنا أسمي نفسي بالعاملة المتفائلة.
And I know there are a lot of us out there.
وأنا أعلم أن هناك الكثير منا.
We have ideas for how to make things better,
لدينا أفكار حول كيفية جعل الأمور أفضل،
and I want to share three of them that we've picked up in our own work.
وأنا أريد أن أشارك ثلاثة منها تلقيناها في عملنا.
Idea number one:
الفكرة رقم واحد:
we need news that's built on deep-domain knowledge.
نحن بحاجة إلى أخبار مبنية على معرفة عميقة بالميدان.
Given the waves and waves of layoffs at newsrooms across the country,
نظرًا لموجات التسريح من العمل الرائجة في غرف الأخبار بجميع أنحاء البلاد،
we've lost the art of specialization.
فقدنا فن التخصص.
Beat reporting is an endangered thing.
إن المراسلة السبقية معرضة للخطر.
When it comes to foreign news,
عندما يتعلق الأمر بالأخبار الأجنبية،
the way we can fix that is by working with more local journalists,
الطريقة التي يمكننا أن نصلح بها ذلك هي بالعمل مع عدد أكبر من الصحفيين المحليين،
not just fixers who fetch us phone numbers and sound bites.
وليس فقط أشخاصًا يجلبون لنا أرقام هواتف وتسجيلات صوتية.
Our local reporters in Syria and across Africa and across Asia
يجلب لنا صحفيونا المحليون في سوريا وعبر أفريقيا وآسيا
bring us stories that we certainly would not have found on our own.
قصصًا لن نستطيع بالتأكيد العثور عليها بمفردنا.
Like this one from the suburbs of Damascus, about a wheelchair race
مثل هذه القصة من ضواحي دمشق، حول سباق للكراسي المتحركة
that gave hope to those wounded in the war.
الأمر الذي أعطى الأمل للمصابين في الحرب.
Or this one from Sierra Leone,
أو هذه من سيراليون،
about a local chief who curbed the spread of Ebola
عن زعيم محلي كبح جماح انتشار فيروس الإيبولا
by self-organizing a quarantine in his district.
عبر تنظيمه لحجْر صحي في منطقته.
Or this one from the border of Pakistan,
أو هذه من الحدود الباكستانية،
about Afghan refugees being forced to return home before they are ready,
حول اللاجئين الأفغان الذين يُجبرون على العودة إلى ديارهم قبل أن يتجهزوا،
under the threat of police intimidation.
تحت تهديد ترهيب الشرطة.
Our local journalists are our mentors.
صحفيونا المحليون هم موجهونا.
They teach us something new every day,
إنهم يعلموننا شيئًا جديدًا كل يوم،
and they bring us stories that are important for all of us to know.
ويجلبون لنا قصصا من المهم أن نعرفها جميعا.
Idea number two:
الفكرة الثانية:
we need a kind of Hippocratic oath for the news industry,
نحن بحاجة إلى شئ مثل "قسَم أبقراط" لصناعة الأخبار،
a pledge to first do no harm.
تعهد أول بعدم التسبب في أي ضرر.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Journalists need to be tough.
الصحفيون في حاجة إلى أن يكونوا أقوياء.
We need to speak truth to power,
نحن بحاجة إلى قول الحقيقة للسلطة،
but we also need to be responsible.
ولكن علينا أيضا أن نكون علي قدر المسؤولية.
We need to live up to our own ideals,
نحن بحاجة إلى الارتقاء إلى مستوى مثلنا العليا،
and we need to recognize
ونحن بحاجة إلى الاعتراف
when what we're doing could potentially harm society,
حين يكون ما نقوم به من المحتمل أن يضر المجتمع،
where we lose track of journalism as a public service.
حين نفقد رؤيتنا للصحافة كخدمة عامة.
I watched us cover the Ebola crisis.
لقد شاهدتُ تغطيتنا لأزمة الإيبولا.
We launched Ebola Deeply. We did our best.
أطلقنا "Ebola Deeply". بذلنا قصارى جهدنا.
But what we saw was a public
ولكن ما رأيناه هو جمهور
that was flooded with hysterical and sensational coverage,
غمرته التغطية الهستيرية والمثيرة،
sometimes inaccurate, sometimes completely wrong.
غير الدقيقة أحيانًا، والخاطئة تمامًا في أحيان أخرى.
Public health experts tell me that that actually cost us in human lives,
أخبرني خبراء الصحة العامة أن هذا كلفنا حياة مجموعة من الأشخاص،
because by sparking more panic and by sometimes getting the facts wrong,
لأنه بإثارة المزيد من الذعر والحصول أحيانًا على وقائع خاطئة،
we made it harder for people to resolve
نجعل من الصعب على الناس معرفة
what was actually happening on the ground.
ما كان يحدث فعلاً على أرض الواقع.
All that noise made it harder to make the right decisions.
كل ذلك الصخب جعل اتخاذ القرارات الصائبة صعبًا.
We can do better as an industry,
يمكننا القيام بما هو أفضل كصناعة،
but it requires us recognizing how we got it wrong last time,
ولكن هذا يتطلب منا معرفة ما جعلنا نفشل في المرة الأولى،
and deciding not to go that way next time.
ونقرر عدم السير في هذا الطريق في المرة القادمة.
It's a choice.
إنه خيار.
We have to resist the temptation to use fear for ratings.
علينا أن نقاوم إغراء استخدام الخوف من التصنيفات.
And that decision has to be made in the individual newsroom
وهذا القرار يجب أن يتم في غرفة الأخبار الفردية
and with the individual news executive.
ومع رئيس التحرير.
Because the next deadly virus that comes around
لأن الفيروس القاتل المقبل
could be much worse and the consequences much higher,
يمكن أن يكون أسوأ بكثير والعواقب وخيمة أكثر،
if we do what we did last time;
إذا كررنا ما فعلناه آخر مرة.
if our reporting isn't responsible and it isn't right.
إذا كانت تقاريرنا غير مسؤولة وغير صحيحة.
The third idea?
الفكرة الثالثة؟
We need to embrace complexity
نحن بحاجة إلى احتضان التعقيد
if we want to make sense of a complex world.
إذا كنا نريد فهم عالم معقد.
Embrace complexity --
احتضان التعقيد -
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
not treat the world simplistically, because simple isn't accurate.
لا أن نتعامل مع العالم ببساطة، لأن البساطة غير دقيقة.
We live in a complex world.
نحن نعيش في عالم معقد.
News is adult education.
الأخبار هي التعليم الخاص بالكبار.
It's our job as journalists to get elbow deep in complexity
إنها مهمتنا كصحفيين أن نتعمق في التعقيد
and to find new ways to make it easier for everyone else to understand.
ونجد طرقًا جديدة لتسهيل الفهم على الجميع.
If we don't do that,
إذا لم نفعل ذلك،
if we pretend there are just simple answers,
إذا تظاهرنا أن هناك أجوبة بسيطة فقط،
we're leading everyone off a steep cliff.
فنحن نقود الجميع نحو حافة جرف شديد الانحدار.
Understanding complexity is the only way to know the real threats
إن فهم التعقيد هو الطريقة الوحيدة لمعرفة التهديدات الحقيقية
that are around the corner.
المشرفة على الحدوث.
It's our responsibility to translate those threats
إن من مسؤوليتنا نقل تلك التهديدات
and to help you understand what's real,
ومساعدتكم على استيعاب ما هو حقيقي،
so you can be prepared and know what it takes to be ready
لكي تكونوا متأهبين وعلى علم بما يلزم لتكونوا مستعدين
for what comes next.
لما سيأتي مستقبلًا.
I am an industrious optimist.
أنا عاملة متفائلة.
I do believe we can fix what's broken.
أنا أؤمن أنه يمكننا إصلاح ما تلف.
We all want to.
نحن جميعا نريد ذلك.
There are great journalists out there doing great work --
هناك صحفيون كثر يقومون بعمل عظيم --
we just need new formats.
نحن فقط بحاجة إلى صيغ جديدة.
I honestly believe this is a time of reawakening,
أعتقد بصدق أنه قد حان وقت نهضتنا،
reimagining what we can do.
لإعادة تصور ما يمكننا القيام به.
I believe we can fix what's broken.
أنا أعتقد أنه يمكننا إصلاح ما تلف.
I know we can fix the news.
أنا أعلم أنه يمكننا إصلاح الأخبار.
I know it's worth trying,
وأوقن أن هذا يستحق المحاولة،
and I truly believe that in the end,
وأعتقد بحق أننا وفي نهاية المطاف،
we're going to get this right.
سننجز الأمر على أكمل وجه.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)